Guide to the James Cummings Bonbright Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
James Cummings Bonbright Papers
1921-1983.
Bonbright, James C. (James Cummings), 1891-1985.
2 linear ft (ca. 2,000 items in 4 boxes).
Columbia University, Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
MS#0131
4078489
This collection contains the papers of James Cummings Bonbright, Columbia University professor of finance and Chairman of New York State Power Authority.
Biographical Note
James Cummings Bonbright, 1891-1985 (Columbia Ph.D., 1921), professor of finance, Columbia University, 1920-1961; Vice-Chairman and Chairman, N.Y. State Power Authority, 1934-1947; consultant on finance of public utilities.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, reports, notes, documents and printed materials chiefly concerning the regulation and finance of public utilities. The correspondence is with other professors, officials of federal and state utility commissions and public utility companies such as Gordon E. Carey, Commonwealth Edison Company, Joseph C. Eastman, Interstate Commerce Commission, the Tennessee Valley Authority, and the New York State Power Authority. Major correspondents include Louis D. Brandeis, Felix Frankfurter, Herbert H. Lehman, Wayne Morse, and Franklin D. Roosevelt. Also included is one group photograph of Bonbright with members of the Columbia University Economics Department, including Edwin R. A. Seligman and Wesley Clair Mitchell.
Arrangement
Selective items cataloged; remainder arranged alphabetically by personal or corporate name. This collection is arranged in one series:
Series I: James Cummings Bonbright Papers, 1921-1983
Subjects
Brandeis, Louis Dembitz, 1856-1941.; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965.; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963.; Morse, Wayne L. (Wayne Lyman), 1900-1974.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Seligman, Edwin R. A. (Edwin Robert Anderson), 1861-1939.; Mitchell, Wesley C. (Wesley Clair), 1874-1948.; Public utilities--Law and legislation.; Letters.; Correspondence.; Photoprints.; Economists--United States--20th century.
Acquisition
10/09/86 M-88-01-29 Bonbright, Mrs. James C. Gift
Gift of Mrs. James C. Bonbright, 1986.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: Box 2-4. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
- Series I: James Cummings Bonbright Papers, 1921-1983
  - Cataloged Correspondence and Documents
    - Brandeis, Louis Dembitz (Box 1)
    - Burns, Arthur Francis (Box 1)
    - Clark, John Maurice (Box 1)
    - Dewey, Thomas E. (Box 1)
    - Douglas, Paul Howard (Box 1)
    - Douglas, William Orville (Box 1)
    - Frankfurter, Felix (Box 1)
    - Hutchins, Robert Maynard (Box 1)
    - Lehman, Herbert H. (Box 1)
    - Mitchell, Wesley Clair (Box 1)
    - Morse, Wayne (Box 1)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Box 1)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Mrs. F.D.) (Box 1)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano (Box 1)
    - Smith, Alfred E. (Box 1)
  - Arranged Correspondence, Manuscripts and Documents
    - A - Am (Box 1)
    - American Philosophical Society (Box 1)
    - American Telephone and Telegraph Company (Box 1)
    - Anderson, Arthur, & Co. (Box 1)
    - B - Ba (Box 1)
    - Baxter, William (Box 1)
    - Bl (Box 1)
    - Bliss, John Alden (Box 1)
    - Bo - Br (Box 1)
    - Bu (Box 1)
    - C - Ce (Box 2)
    - Ch (Box 2)
    - Chicago and Northwestern Railway Affadvits of 1957 (Box 2)
    - Coa (Box 2)
    - Columbia Gas System - Deman (or Allocation) Correspondence (Box 2)
    - Columbia University - President, Secretary, Provost (Box 2)
    - Columbia University Press
      - Reviews - of Principles of rates (Box 2)
      - Complimentary copies of principles (Box 2)
    - Columbia University Council for Research in the Social Sciences
      - (my project 170) (Box 2)
      - The "Bonbright" Report (Box 2)
    - Commonwealth Edison Co. (Box 2)
    - Coo - Cou (Box 2)
    - Corey, Gordon (Box 2)
    - Cr - Cu (Box 2)
    - D - Da (Box 2)
    - De - Di (Box 2)
    - Dean's Railroad Rate - documents of April (?) 1968 (Box 2)
    - Dohr, James L. (Box 2)
    - Don - Du (Box 2)
    - E - Em (Box 2)
    - Eastman, Joseph B. (Box 2)
    - En (Box 2)
    - Fa - Fe (Box 2)
    - Federal Power Commission (Box 2)
    - Fi (Box 2)
    - Fo (Box 2)
    - Ford Foundation Fellowship - Non- Financial acct. no. 327-957-19 (Box 2)
    - Ge (Box 3)
    - General Public Utilities Stucy - cost allocation (Box 3)
    - Gi (Box 3)
    - Governor's Committee on Power Resources (Box 3)
    - Gr (Box 3)
    - Har - Haw (Box 3)
    - Hea - Hel (Box 3)
    - Her (Box 3)
    - Hi (Box 3)
    - Ho (Box 3)
    - I (Box 3)
    - Interstate Commerce Commission (Box 3)
    - Iowa State Utility Conference 1962, 1963, 1968 (Box 3)
    - J (Box 3)
    - Japanese Friends of 1966 (Box 3)
    - Ka - Ke (Box 3)
    - Ki - Kz (Box 3)
    - La (Box 3)
    - Le (Box 3)
    - Li (Box 3)
    - Lo - Ly (Box 3)
    - Long Island Lights Co. letters (Box 3)
    - Ma (Box 3)
    - Me (Box 3)
    - Mi (Box 3)
    - Mo (Box 3)
    - Na - Ne (Box 4)
    - No (Box 4)
    - New York Telephone Co. 1968 - 69 (Box 4)
    - O (Box 4)
    - P (Box 4)
    - Penn Central - Payment for New Haven R. R. (Box 4)
    - Pl (Box 4)
    - Q (Box 4)
    - R (Box 4)
    - Ro (Box 4)
    - Rockefeller Foundation Grant (Box 4)
    - Roosevelt, President Franklin D. (Box 4)
    - Ross, Clarence (Box 4)
    - Scharff, Maurice (Box 4)
    - Sche - Schw (Box 4)
    - Se (Box 4)
    - Si - Sl (Box 4)
    - Sm - Sp (Box 4)
    - Sta (Box 4)
    - Sti - Str (Box 4)
    - Swidler, Joseph (Box 4)
    - T (Box 4)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority (Box 4)
    - U (Box 4)
    - V (Box 4)
    - Valuation of property (Box 4)
    - Vilarasau, Josie (Box 4)
    - W (Box 4)
    - We (Box 4)
    - Wh (Box 4)
    - X - Y (Box 4)
    - One oversized photograph of James C. Bonbright and Columbia University Economics Department Faculty (Box Map Case 14 - P - 2)